Guide to the University of California, Santa Barbara, Office of Development Collection
Department of Special Collections
University of California, Santa Barbara, Office of Development Collection
ca. 1973-2006
UArch 51
University of California, Santa Barbara. Office of Development
7 linear feet (3 document boxes, 2 card file boxes, 3 photo binder boxes, 2 flat oversize boxes and 6 videotapes).
University of California, Santa Barbara. Library. Dept. of Special Collections Santa Barbara, CA 93106
Collection contains files relating to the UCSB Foundation and other Development Office projects and events. Includes many event photographs.
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from Office of Development.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series I: UCSB Foundation. A subdivision of the Development Office, the foundation promotes and manages donations to UCSB. Contains board and committee files, reports, newsletters, and other materials, arranged alphabetically.
Series II: General. Contains subject files relating to Development Office projects and events as well as published documents such as brochures, pamphlets, memos, etc. Arranged alphabetically.
Series III: Photographs. Contains color and black and white photos, primarily from Development/UCSB Foundation sponsored events. Also includes promotional photos of campus and UCSB administrators used for various purposes. Some photos are boxed loose, others are held in album sheets in binders. There are also two scrapbooks, with some duplication of photos.
Series IV: Videos. Contains five VHS videotapes used at events.
More information about the Office of Development at their website: http://www.ia.ucsb.edu/dev/index.shtml
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
University of California, Santa Barbara. Office of Development
Related Materials
Review, publication of the Office of Development in University Archives Serials.
UCSB Report, publication of Development in University Archives Serials Short Runs.
Follow Up, publication of UCSB Foundation in University Archives Serials.
UCSB Office of University Relations Collection, UArch 92.
UCSB Alumni Association Collection, UArch 69.
UCSB Affiliates Collection, UArch 50.
Office of Development website: http://www.ia.ucsb.edu/dev/index.shtml
- UCSB Foundation, Series I:
  - Adopt a Student Program, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Annual Report
    - "Partners in Philanthropy: The UCSB Foundation Report, 1972-1982" (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - 1983-1986 (Box-folder 1: 3-5)
    - Annual Report of Private Giving, 1990-1994 (Box-folder 1: 6-9)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Meeting minutes, Mar. 13, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Meeting, Nov. 1985 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Meeting agenda, Feb. 9, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Meeting agenda, Apr. 30, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Meeting agenda, Oct. 8, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Meeting materials, Oct. 17, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Meeting agenda, Feb. 18, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 17)
    - Meeting agenda, May 20, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    - Meeting materials, May 20, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 19)
    - Membership list and directory
      - 1991-1993 (Box-folder 1: 20-21)
      - 1993-1996 (Box-folder 2: 1-3)
      - No date (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Calendars, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - "The Campaign for UCSB: Structure and Goals," Critical Plan, Feb. 1983 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "The Campaign for UCSB: University Library,", c. 1990s (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - "The Campaign for UCSB," volunteer handbook, c. 1983 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Chancellor's Council
    - Brochures, c. 1981-1996 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985; 1993-1995 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Coastlines article, "The First Twenty Years of the UCSB Foundation,", Spring 1993 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Committees, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Executive Director's Report to the UCSB Foundation, Oct. 8, 1994 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Follow Up newsletter, 1991 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Nominations Committee
    - Agenda and minutes, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - Documents for study, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Planned Giving Committee
    - Documents for study, c. 1990-1994 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    - Minutes and agenda, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 2: 18)
    - Program drafts, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1995 (Box-folder 2: 20)
- General, Series II:
  - "10 Ways You Can Help UCSB: A Tax-Saving Guide for Making Charitable Gifts,", 1981 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Annual Fund member and fundraising letters, Sept. 15, 1985 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Campaign for UCSB, c. 1983-2006 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Chancellor's Associates, c. 1973-1974 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Chancellor's Council booklet, c. 1987-1994 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Chancellor's Council member and fundraising letters, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "A Development Program for the 1980s,", June 1981 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Events, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "The Events Facility," Campaign Newsletter, Apr. 1979 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Fund for the '80s, 1980 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - "Gifts and Givers: Their Importance to UCSB,", Apr. 1973 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - "Giving Through Trusts and Bequests," (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Hutchins Center member and fundraising letters, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Lancaster Society Recognition Event, Feb. 19, 1999 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Memos, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Pamphlets, 1988-1993 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Parents' Council / Parent's Fund member and fundraising letters, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Parents' Weekend, 1991; 1994 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - "UCSB Donor Honor Roll,", 1988-1989 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - "UCSB's Distinctive Strengths and Qualities...", c. 1980s (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - "UCSB: A Good Investment,", n.d. (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Volunteers for UCSB, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 3: 22)
- Photographs, Series III:
  - Events
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (22 color photos), May 5, 1984 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - [Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (34 color photos), 1985?] (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Getty Reception (139 color photos), Feb. 1986 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Chancellor's Council Lecture and Performance Series (CCLAPS), Walter Capps, speaker, San Ysidro Ranch (3 bw photos), Oct. 16, 1986 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (7 bw photos), May 9, 1986 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - Holiday Dinner (20 color photos), 1986 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - CCLAPS, Bob Kerrey, speaker, at Gevirtz home (4 bw photos), Feb. 26, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - CCLAPS, Juilliard String Quarter (6 bw photos), Apr. 22, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Parent Donor Luncheon (2 bw photos), May 2, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (20 color photos), May 30, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Chancellor's Council Luncheon (2 bw photos), Sept. 25, 1987 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - "A Conversation about Acting" (14 bw photos), Mar. 31, 1988 (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (115 bw and color photos), May 21, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - CCLAPS event, Music Academy (3 bw photos), Nov. 14, [1988?] (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - CCLAPS event, La Jolla Country Club (12 bw and color photos), Nov. 15, [1988?] (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Patrick Stewart, "A Christmas Carol" (37 bw and color photos), Dec. 2-3, 1989 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, Sedgwick Ranch (140 bw and color photos), May 20, 1989 (Box-folder 8: 4)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, Sonell home, Montecito (103 bw and color photos), May 5, 1990 (Box-folder 8: 5)
    - UCSB Foundation event (2 bw photos), Oct. 1990 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (incl. negatives; 155 color photos), 1991 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (12 color photos), May 2, 1992 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (4 color photos), May 1, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Parent's Weekend (incl. negatives; 20 color photos), Nov. 12-13, 1993 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (27 color photos), 1994 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner (239 color photos), May 20, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Chicago reception (6 color photos), Oct. 20, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Parent's Weekend (6 color photos), Nov. 3-4, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Dehlsen Reception (42 color photos), 1998 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Lancaster Society Recognition event (101 color photos), Feb. 19, 1999 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Unknown event (90 color photos), May 15, 1999 (Box-folder 8: 7)
    - Holiday party [?] (37 color photos), 2001 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Lancaster Society Recognition event, (incl. negatives; 96 color photos), Feb. 10, 2001 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Lancaster Society Recognition Reception, H. Pollock Gallery, Summerland (incl. negatives; 71 color photos), Feb. 8, 2002 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Unknown UCSB Foundation event (65 color photos), c. 1994-2002 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Misc. photos and negatives, c. 1990-1995 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Promotional campus and administrator photos (72 bw and color photos, 24 slides and negatives), ca. 1988-1991 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbooks (events listed in order of appearance in scrapbooks)
    - Scrapbook #1 (Box 10)
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 5, 1984
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 9, 1986
      - Parent Donor Luncheon, May 2, 1987
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 30, 1987
      - Chancellor's Council Luncheon, Sept. 25, 1987
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 21, 1988
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 20, 1989
      - Patrick Stewart, "A Christmas Carol,", Dec. 2-3, 1989
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, 1990
      - Parents' Ice Cream Social, Aug. 26, 1990
      - Art museum reception, 1990
      - Holiday party, 1990
    - Scrapbook #2 (Box 11)
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, Tom Toni Schottke[?]'s, May 10, 1997
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 4, 1996
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 4, 1991
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 2, 1992
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 1, 1993
      - Parents' Weekend, Nov. 12-13, 1993
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, Apr. 30, 1994
      - Chancellor's Council Annual Dinner, May 20, 1995
      - Parents' Weekend, Nov. 3-4, 1995
      - Chicago reception, Oct. 20, 1995
- Video, Series IV:
  - ArtsBridge, UC Irvine, Spring 2000 (Cassette V4572/VHS)
  - ArtsBridge loop tape (2 copies) (Cassette V4570-V4571/VHS)
  - UCSB Alumni Achievements in Film Television (Cassette V4573/VHS)
  - UCSB Alumni Achievements in Film Television (revised), (2 copies) (Cassette V4574, 4633/VHS)